<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lluc Puig Codina</title>
    <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lluc Puig Codina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Drawing with Restrictions in MCMC</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/mhrestrictiongeweke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/mhrestrictiongeweke/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}It is often the case that, when simulating from posterior distributions using MCMC, researchers wish to impose restrictions on some parameters.
Two illustrative cases are discussed in Geweke’s Contemporary Bayesian Econometrics and Statistics Example 4.2.2 and 4.3.2 . The following description of the setup (and notation) is taken almost verbatim from Geweke. These examples consider a normal linear regression model with Gaussian disturbances in which the prior of \(\boldsymbol{\beta}\) (the regression coefficient) given \(h\) (precision) is \(\mathscr{N}(\underline{\boldsymbol{\beta}}, \underline{\textbf{H}})\) truncated to a set \(S\subseteq \mathbb{R}^k\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X &gt; MAX for independent but not identically distributed betas</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/abtest_general_formula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/abtest_general_formula/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In this post I provide a general formula for the probability that the realization of a beta random variable is larger than the realizations from a sequence of beta random variables, all of them being independent. Assume \(p_j \sim \mathscr{B}(\alpha_j, \beta_j)\). We have J+1 independent but not identically distributed beta random variables, indexed from 0 to J, and we are interested in calculating \(\mathbb{P}(p_0 &amp;gt; max\{p_1,\dots,p_J\})\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth-at-Risk IMF Tool</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/growth_at_risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/growth_at_risk/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has been using Growth-at-Risk, a macro-econometric tool developed by them to assess risks to economic growth, in several article IV country reports (Albania, Portugal and Singapore 2018), Chapter 2 of the IMF Global Financial Conditions Report since October 2017 and so on. The tool is built taking the methodology developed in the AER April 2019 paper Vulnerable Growth. I have several disagreements about the statistical procedures used and the interpretation of the results in the AER paper, which you can read here in my working papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tests for correct specification of conditional predictive densities</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/rossi_cond_density_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/rossi_cond_density_tests/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}I have implemented the statistical tests of Rossi and Sekhposyan (2019) in R. You can find the codes in the following Github repo. Two tests, a Kolmogorov-Smirnov test and an Cràmer-von Mises test, are implemented to assess the correct specification of rolling window conditional distribution out-of-sample forecasts, one and multiple steps ahead.
Thew hole idea of the test is the following: let \(X\) be a random variable with cdf \(F_X\) (with well defined \(F_X^{-1}\)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acerbi &amp; Szekely Unconditional Expected Shortfall Test</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/expectedshortfalltest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/expectedshortfalltest/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Python implementation of the Direct Expected Shortfall Test of Acerbi and Szekely (2014).I don’t know of any implementation of such test in Python. The test has been implemented in MatLab. The backtesting of Expected Shortfall has long been a difficult task due to the lack of elicitibility. The test I’ve implemented is the second test of Acerbi and Szekely and it’s full details are in the reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles and the Behavioural New Keynesian Model</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/determinacy_gabaix_new_keynesian_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/determinacy_gabaix_new_keynesian_model/</guid>
      <description>Herein I conduct similar policy experiments to those of Carlstrom et al. (2012) with a Behavioural New Keynesian (BNK) model, instead of the standard New Keynesian model (only) or a sticky information model. The BNK model does a good job of solving previous issues with the standard model (as already noted by Gabaix).
All of this work is already, explicitly or implicitly, in the cited articles, so I wouldn’t claim to show anything new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La universitat gratuïta es ajudar els rics</title>
      <link>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/universitat_gratuita_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://llucpuigcodina.github.io/posts/universitat_gratuita_2/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Recentment s’ha publicat un article escrit per dos companys i jo mateix al diari Ara. El podeu llegir aquí.
També va aparèixer a la versió impresa del 11 de Gener de 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
